<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[DoggieDashboard.com Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-13T13:00:17-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[DoggieDashboard.com]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Start a Doggie Daycare From Home]]></title>
    <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/13/how-to-start-a-doggie-daycare-from-home/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-13T12:49:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/13/how-to-start-a-doggie-daycare-from-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever imagined starting a doggie daycare from the comfort of you home? You get to run a business from the comfort of your house and you don&rsquo;t need to rent out a business space. However, there are some questions you should ask yourself before you try to start a doggie daycare from your home.</p>

<h2>Does My City Zoning Regulations Permit Doggie Daycares in Residential Buildings?</h2>

<hr />

<p>It&rsquo;s all fun and games to imagine running a doggie daycare from the comforts of your house, but you&rsquo;ll need to make sure that you&rsquo;re doing everything legally. One of the most important issues is contacting your local city government and asking them how <a href="http://www.cyburbia.org/forums/showthread.php?t=46395">zoning rules work in your city</a>. Most cities don&rsquo;t let you run a commerical business from a residentially-zoned property. Therefore, you&rsquo;ll either need to get your property re-zoned as a dual commercial/residential property, or you&rsquo;ll need to get an allowance from the city to run a business from your home.</p>

<h2>How Will my Homeowner&rsquo;s Insurance be Affected by Having a Doggie Daycare?</h2>

<hr />

<p>Once you&rsquo;ve figured out the zoning issues with starting a doggie daycare from your home, it&rsquo;s time to look into your homeowner&rsquo;s insurance policy and figure out what will happen once you start a business. You might get lucky and your homeowners insurance will cover your business. However, the more common situation is that you will need to buy <a href="http://www.business-insurers.com/doggy-day-care-insurance-and-boarding-kennel-insurance">commercial business insurance for your doggie daycare</a>. This will cover any injuries that the pets might cause, as well as any accidents that occur on your property.</p>

<h2>Am I Ready to Bring my Work Life into my Home Life?</h2>

<hr />

<p>It sounds great to have a business that you can run from your home, but you also need to realize that you&rsquo;ll be mixing your social life with your business life. When your business is connected to your house, it&rsquo;s hard to &ldquo;unplug&rdquo; from work, because work is always right around the corner. Make sure you figure out how you&rsquo;ll create the work/life balance necessary to keep yourself sane.</p>

<h2>Are My Neighbors Going to Complain About Having so Many Dogs on my Property?</h2>

<hr />

<p>Last but not least, if you&rsquo;re located in a city, you&rsquo;re going to need to make sure your neighbors are okay with you starting a doggie daycare from your home. There are going to be dogs barking at all hours of the day and if your neighbors get upset, they can complain to the city and you might have to shut down your business. Perhaps it would be wise to invest in a pole-shed where your can let the dogs outside and if they bark, the sound is contained. Just make sure to keep your neighbors happy, because there is nothing worse for a business than angry neighbors.</p>

<p>If you already own a doggie daycare and need a way to keep track of your clients and pets, check out <a href="http://doggiedashboard.com">DoggieDashboard.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 Questions to Ask Before Starting a Doggie Daycare]]></title>
    <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/11/3-questions-to-ask-before-starting-a-doggie-daycare/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-11T20:08:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/11/3-questions-to-ask-before-starting-a-doggie-daycare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many people want to start a doggie daycare business. It&rsquo;s a great way to <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/205312">make some extra income</a>, and you get to be your own boss. Your employees are people are you get to hire, and your clients, dogs, are pretty fun to deal with. However, running a doggie daycare isn&rsquo;t all fun and games. There are some important issues that you should take into consideration before you start your doggie daycare. Here are three questions to ask yourself before starting a dog boarding business.</p>

<h3>Am I Start a Doggie Daycare for the Money or for my Love of Animals?</h3>

<hr />

<p>A lot of people start businesses because they want to make money. However, if making money is your only concern, there are much better businesses to start that a doggie daycare. Lot and lots of work will go into your business, and it will take time away from your social life and family. If you don&rsquo;t have a love for animals, the money won&rsquo;t help. You need to love what you do with your time. They call it work for a reason. Some days will be great and others will not be so great. However, each day is a new challenge. If you get up every morning and are grateful for being able to care for animals while their parents are away, you&rsquo;re in the right mindset. If you wake up every day thinking about the profit, go become a stock broker!</p>

<h3>How Long can I Run this Business Before I Need to Make a Profit?</h3>

<hr />

<p>A lot of people have fantasies of starting a business but don&rsquo;t think about the profit side of the business and when they will <a href="https://www.sba.gov/content/breakeven-analysis">hit their breakeven point</a>. Yes, running a doggie daycare can be a profitable business, but you&rsquo;re going to need to be able to make a profit to pay your employees, insurance, bonding, etc. Therefore, it&rsquo;s a good idea to start thinking about how long your business can run before it will need to turn a profit. It&rsquo;s always wise to give yourself a year of time to get up and running. That might seem like a long time, but getting clients and building word-of-mouth advertising takes time. Don&rsquo;t let your business die because you didn&rsquo;t have enough reserve funds to keep it alive.</p>

<h3>Is This Business Going to be my Only Source of Income or Will it be a Side Business?</h3>

<hr />

<p>Last but not least, you need to figure out if your doggie daycare business is going to be a full-time pursuit, or if you&rsquo;re going to hire someone to run the day-to-day operations while you stay at your corporate gig. For most people, it&rsquo;s smart to keep their day job during the planning and building stages of the business. It will take time to find a facility, sigh all the paperwork, get it built out etc. These are things you can do on the weekends while you&rsquo;re still working your corporate gig. Once you are finally ready to start the business, maybe you should think about transitioning to a part-time role at your company. If you have employees, they will want to know that you&rsquo;re in it for the long haul. Don&rsquo;t leave them hanging.</p>

<p>Good luck opening your doggie daycare, and if you&rsquo;re looking for a great way to manage your business, check out <a href="http://doggiedashboard.com">DoggieDashboard</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Best Locations for Starting a Doggie Daycare Business]]></title>
    <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/05/5-best-locations-for-starting-a-doggie-daycare-business/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T17:03:38-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/05/5-best-locations-for-starting-a-doggie-daycare-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting a doggie daycare and boarding business can be a very profitable business. This <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/80654">Entrepreneur Article</a> lists it as one of the top 9 pet business that you shoudl start. However, havintg the idea of starting a doggie daycare and actually starting one are completely different. Check through our blog archive above to see all of our posts about starting a doggie daycare. This post will focus solely on 5 top locations for doggie daycares.</p>

<h2>Abandonded Warehouses in your Cities Business District</h2>

<hr />

<p>This seems to be the most popular method of opening doggie daycares these days. Since so many manufacturing jobs have gone overseas, there are a lot of old factories and warehouses that sit abandoned in most major cities. Most owners will happily lease you the building at a great rate, just to cut their losses. With a little most to clean it up and give it a touch of warmth, you&rsquo;ll have a great doggie daycare on your hands.</p>

<h2>Large Plot of Land in the Cheaper Outskirts</h2>

<hr />

<p>If you&rsquo;re going to be focusing more on large breed dogs, you&rsquo;re going to need space. No pet owner is going to board their large breed at a facility that doesn&rsquo;t have adequate running room. The benefit of boarding large breed dogs is that you can charge a little bit more money for them. So, if you&rsquo;re thinking you&rsquo;re doing large breed, it&rsquo;s best to find a cheap plot of land in the country-side and fence in a few acres. Give the dogs 100% free access to roam and just make sure to put muzzles on any of the dogs that might have social issues. You can check your pet records on <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a> to see if pets have any issues.</p>

<h2>Small residential house with a Fenced in Yard</h2>

<hr />

<p>This one works great for doggie daycares that are going to focus more on small animals, and not so much on big dogs. If you can find an older small house in your city, especially one that has a fenced in back yard, you have your entire business right there! Take one of the rooms for your business office, and let your pets roam free in the other rooms. Dogs will feel much more comfortable if they can sleep on an old couch instead of inside a kennel and their parents will be MUCH happier if they know their little Lassie is napping in the sun on the floor of the livingroom. Add a doggie door to the property and you don&rsquo;t even need to worry about letting the dogs out.</p>

<h2>Any Building in Close Proximity to a Public Park</h2>

<hr />

<p>Word of mouth advertising is a great way to get the word out, but so is visual advertising. If you&rsquo;re near a public park, there&rsquo;s a good chance you&rsquo;ll have plenty of people taking peeks at your business, and maybe even grabbing some flyers when they walk by. It&rsquo;s all about getting the word out. Perhaps you can have your employee walk a whole herd of your dogs one day and hand out flyers when pet owners ask why she/he has SO MANY dogs.</p>

<h2>In the Heart of Downtown</h2>

<hr />

<p>This one might seem like the craziest ideas, but many of your wealthiest pet owners also live right in the heart of the city. If they have pets that they need boarded, they most likely arent willing to drive way out of their way to the doggie daycare. With a few investors to help fund the build-out, you can own a very nice property in the heart of your city. Because people are going to realize the convenience of your location, they&rsquo;re going to be willing to pay much more money for it as well. Would you rather have 10 dogs at $10/day in a country facility, or 2 dogs at $50/day in a downtown facility? Pretty simple, right?</p>

<p>We hope you enjoyed this article. Pleaes remember <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a> if you ever need free doggie daycare software for your business.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 Advertising Strategies to Get More Doggie Daycare Customers]]></title>
    <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/02/6-advertising-strategies-to-get-more-doggie-daycare-customers/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/12/02/6-advertising-strategies-to-get-more-doggie-daycare-customers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a></p>

<h2>Take Out an Ad in your Local Newspaper</h2>

<hr />

<p>This might seem like the most basic form of advertising, but that&rsquo;s because&hellip;it is! However, local newspapers, like Denver&rsquo;s WestWord or the Miami New Times are a great way to focus in on the younger demographic. Pay a graphic designer to make you an attractive banner advertisement, and run it for a few weeks in your local paper. Make sure to track results so you know if your ROI is good. You&rsquo;d be surprised how well old fashion advertising can still work.</p>

<h2>Use Google AdWords to Do Location-Specific Advertising in your City</h2>

<hr />

<p><a href="http://google.com/adwords">Google AdWords</a> is a great way to advertise your doggie daycare business. With the location-based advertising that AdWords lets you do, you&rsquo;ll be able to have your advertisements show only in the city where your business is located. You will most likely have to pay about $1 every time someone clicks on your Google advertising, but if every 30 clicks produces a new client, that&rsquo;s a $30 cost per acquisition. Great!</p>

<h2>Sponsor a Local Sports Team of Young Adults</h2>

<hr />

<p>This is one of the oldest tricks in the book to get cheap advertising for your doggie daycare. Go find your local 20-something sports league and offer to sponsor a team. You&rsquo;ll be required to pay for their jersies(which will have your logo and website address), and you&rsquo;ll most likely need to pay their entrance fee into the league. However, every single week, your brand will get in front of hundreds of new eyes. With many young adult couples deciding to get a pet instead of have children, these are exactly the kind of people you want to be seeing your business.</p>

<h2>Use Facebook Geo-Targeting and Like-Focusing to Find Pet Owners</h2>

<hr />

<p>As much as Facebook can be a <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/elandekel/2013/01/22/facebook-pages-are-a-bad-investment-for-small-businesses/">money-suck for small businesses</a>, it also serves a great purpose. If lets you focus on people with very specific interests. Using a very small marketing budget at the start, go some geo-located advertising in your city. Focus on users that have dogs and are located within a certain radius of your zipcode. With some testing, you&rsquo;ll be able to hone in and target the exact users that you&rsquo;re looking for.</p>

<h2>Find Bring-Your-Dog-to-Work-Companies and Offer Them a Deal</h2>

<hr />

<p>Many newer tech companies offer their employees the ability to bring their dogs/cats to work. This is a great perk to employees and a great business opportunity for you. Contact the HR department, and tell them you&rsquo;d like to partner with them as their official doggie daycare and boarding facility. When employees head out of town, you can offer them a discount on their service(and have their employer pick up the difference.) Imagine you usually charge $40/night at your facility. You can charge the employees of Company X only $20 and have their employer pick up the remaining $20. This is a great benefit they can offer their employees and you&rsquo;ll get a ton of new business.</p>

<h2>Offer Dog Pickup and Delivery and Wrap Your Vehicle in Advertising</h2>

<hr />

<p>This advertising strategy might be better for dog boarding facilities than for doggie daycare facilities, but since <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a> works with both types of businesses, we thought we should mention it. Many pet owners are busy in the morning. The last thing they want to do is drive out of the way to your pet boarding facility. By employing a pickup and delivery driver, you can schedule to have pets picked up and dropped off at a particiular hour of the day(for a fee of course). You&rsquo;ll be able to offer needed service to your clients, and they will appreciate it with giving you long-term business and maybe even some referral business.</p>

<p>If you have the disposable income, think about <a href="http://solutions.3m.com/wps/portal/3M/en_EU/3MGraphics/GraphicSolutions/Applications/CarWrapping/">wrapping your pickup vehicle</a> in marketing materials. This can be a great way to get your brand in front of hundreds of eyes every day. If someone with a dog sees your van at a stoplight and sees &ldquo;Pickup and Delivery&rdquo;, they just might remember your name and call you in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Ways to Grow Your Doggie Daycare]]></title>
    <link href="https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/11/20/5-ways-to-grow-your-doggie-daycare/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-20T15:56:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://doggiedashboard.com/blog/2014/11/20/5-ways-to-grow-your-doggie-daycare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running a doggie daycare is hard work. You&rsquo;ve spent hundreds of hours building your facility, getting all your business licenses and now it’s time to start making some money. Luckily, we here at <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a> are here to help. Here are 5 tips for increasing the business at your doggie daycare.</p>

<h2>Offer a First Month Free Program</h2>

<hr />

<p>This might sound counter-productive to most business owners, but offering a free month is one of the best things you can do to increase your business. Most pet owners are looking for a long-term doggie daycare. They don&rsquo;t anticipate switching between numerous different doggie daycares. The switching costs are also quite high. Dog owners want to feel comfortable with the people who are taking care of their dogs. If you can get someone to sign up for a free month, and blow them away with good service, you&rsquo;re more than likely going to get a long-term doggie daycare client in return. So toughen up, take a one-month hit on your revenue, and start giving our those free month passes ASAP.</p>

<h2>Start a Refer a Friend Affiliate Deal</h2>

<hr />

<p>There&rsquo;s a very good chance that you&rsquo;re current doggie daycare clients are friends with other dog owners. That&rsquo;s just how pet owners are, they tend to stick together. If you haven&rsquo;t yet, it would be a great idea to start a <a href="http://www.biscuitsandbath.com/referrals.aspx">doggie daycare refer-a-friend program</a>. It can be as easy as giving away a free week of service for every client that your current customers refer. You&rsquo;ll build you customer base while also keeping your current customers happy by giving them a great discount for helping grow your business.</p>

<h2>Partner with Local Vet Clinics</h2>

<hr />

<p>Vet clinics are a great place to look for new clients. Most vet clinics are more than willing to refer you to their clients. It might take a bit of time to generate a relationship, but once you have a solid relationship set up, you&rsquo;ll be able to reap the benefits. Vets are one of the first places that new pet owners go, and if they&rsquo;ve got your business in their rolodex, you&rsquo;ll start getting new clients without doing any work. You might want to pay the vet clinics a referral bonus, that but that&rsquo;s an issue for a future blog post.</p>

<h2>Increase Your Doggie Daycare Service Offerings</h2>

<hr />

<p>Does your doggie daycare offer grooming? Does your doggie daycare <a href="http://www.doggyhaven.com/daycare.htm">offer in-house vet checkups</a>? Does your vet offer baths? These are all simple things that you can start including in your doggie daycare offerings. Most vets will happily do a weekly housecall to your doggie daycare facility. It&rsquo;s just a matter of having your clients sign up for the &ldquo;weekly checkups&rdquo; that you offer. You&rsquo;ll get a cut of the business that the vet charges, and your cients will be more happy as a result.</p>

<h2>Create Stronger Customer Relations with Doggie Daycare Software</h2>

<hr />

<p>Doggie daycares rely on one thing more than any other, good customer service. People are putting their dogs in your trust. If you lose that trust, your business will fail, it&rsquo;s that simple. Customer service can be the make or break for your business. Good customer service will drive more clients, bad customer service will put you out of business before you know it. A great way to increase your customer service is to use a doggie daycare software tool like <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">DoggieDashboard</a>. With DoggieDashboard, you can keep track of your clients, and pets, and even send emails to your clients from directly inside the app. It&rsquo;s totally free and helps you keep an open line of communication between your clients and yourself.</p>

<p>We hope you&rsquo;ve enjoyed these tips to increasing your doggie daycare business. Best of luck and keep DoggieDashboard in mind for when you need a <a href="https://doggiedashboard.com/">free doggie daycare software tool</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
